What imprisons desires of the heart?
Far from Heaven is a drama, romance film directed by Todd Haynes.
In 1950s Connecticut, a housewife's life is upended by a marital
crisis and mounting racial tensions in society.
Cathy Whitaker, played by Julianne Moore.
Frank Whitaker, played by Dennis Quaid.
Raymond Deagan, played by Dennis Haysbert.
Eleanor Fine, played by Patricia Clarkson.
Sybil, played by Viola Davis.
Dr. Bowman, played by James Rebhorn.
Far from Heaven is a 2002 historical romantic drama film written and directed by Todd Haynes and
starring Julianne Moore, Dennis Quaid, Dennis Haysbert and Patricia Clarkson.
Moore plays a 1950s housewife living in wealthy suburban Connecticut as
she sees her seemingly perfect life begin to fall apart.
Haynes intended the film as an homage to the melodramas of Douglas Sirk (especially 1955's All That Heaven Allows, 1956's Written
on the Wind, and 1959's Imitation of Life), which explored issues of social entrapment and taboo relationships.
Haynes extended those subjects to include interracial love, gender roles,
sexual orientation, and class in the context of 1950s America.
The film premiered at the Venice Film Festival, where Moore won the Volpi Cup for Best Actress, and
cinematographer Edward Lachman won a prize for Outstanding Individual Contribution.
Far from Heaven received numerous accolades, including four Academy Award
nominations, including Best Actress for Moore and Best Original Screenplay.
Moore was also nominated for a Golden Globe and Screen Actors Guild Award, while Quaid was
nominated for Best Supporting Actor at the Golden Globes and Screen Actors Guild Awards.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, housewife,
botanist, connecticut, interracial relationship.
The tone is emotional.